https://www.assured-ltd.co.uk/privacy/

Navigation HomeMain MenuHomeAboutAbout Assured Fire & SecurityAssured HistoryWhy Choose Assured?AccreditationsOur CustomersOur PartnersCase StudiesVideosPrivacy PolicyFire ProtectionInstallationFire Alarm SystemFire SuppressionEmergency Lighting and SignsFire ExtinguishersFire Safety TrainingFire Risk AssessmentDry RisersWet RisersDisabled RefugeService & MaintenanceSecurity ProtectionInstallationIntruder AlarmsAlarm MonitoringCCTV SystemsAccess ControlService & MaintenanceBrochureNewsAssured NewsIndustry NewsBlogContact Us
Return to ContentHome » Privacy Policy Welcome to Assured Fire and Security Ltd Privacy PolicyThis Privacy Policy is meant to help you understand what data we collect, why we collect it, and what we do with it.Our Privacy Policy follows the legal guidelines of the general data protection regulations (GDPR) which came into force on 25/05/2018This privacy policy explains:What personal information we collect and howHow we use that information.Information we shareProtecting your personal informationData RetentionLinks to other websitesHonesty and TransparencyWe’ve tried to keep it as simple as possible, but if you’re not familiar with terms like cookies and IP addresses, then read about these key terms first.Your privacy matters to Assured Fire and Security Ltd so whether you are new to Assured or an existing customer, please do take the time to get to know our practices – and if you have any questions contact us.What Personal Information we collect and howWe collect information so that we can provide a better service to all of our customers and a better website with improved navigation.We and the third party companies we work with use various technologies to collect and store information when you visit Assured Fire and Security Ltd.’s website and this may include using cookies or similar technologies to identify your browser or device. We also use these technologies to collect and store information when you interact with services we offer This information may include basic personal data such as:Your name.Your work or home address.Your email addresses.Your telephone numbers.Your place of work.Your job titles.The nature of your enquiry.We collect information on the following ways:1. Information you provide us –when signing up to our buyer’s guides, requesting a quote and/or requesting a survey, we will ask for personal information like your name, email address and telephone number2. Information we gain from your website journey -  We collect information about what services your interested and how you gain access to our website through IP tracking and Cookie tracking through third parties.Such information includes:Device information – what device has been used to reach our websiteLocation – where our visitors are located within in and out of the UKDetails of how you have used our website, such as your search queries, the pages visited, time spent on our website and your activity whilst on our websiteFrequency – how often you have visited our websiteYour visit to this website is done so on a voluntarily basis. All information and data collected on this website is done so on a voluntarily basis. All information and exchanges between you and our business is done so with consent.We will keep all information and data collected to a minimum and will not seek sensitive information through our website. Sensitive information is defined as being data relating to gender, occupation, ethnic origin, mental state, physical state, orientations including political, religious or other points of view.If you believe that your information and data is being used in a manner outside of our normal business operations you should contact us using the details found below. How we use information that we collectUnder the new data protection law starting in May 2018 we have a number of lawful reasons that we can use (or 'process') your personal information. One of the lawful reasons is called 'legitimate interests'. Broadly speaking Legitimate Interests means that we can process your personal information if: “We have a genuine and legitimate reason and we are not harming any of your rights and interests”So, what does this mean? When you provide your personal details to us we use your information for our legitimate business interests to carry out our work of protecting, people and property with pride professionalism and integrity, though, we will also carefully consider and balance any potential impact on you and your rights.We will process the personal information you have supplied to us to conduct and manage our business to enable us to give you the most appropriate information on the Fire and Security industry, our service delivery and products and provide the best and most secure experience.We also use this information to offer you tailored content – by providing you with more articles that you have shown as interest in and more offers relevant to your interests.This site uses ResponseTap to better understand where phone calls to our business come from. The following cookies are always set when a visitor has JavaScript and cookies enabled (unless otherwise stated):adiV Contains a visitor ID for a website visitor, which is used by ResponseTap to track a visitor over time. This cookie has an expiry set on a 1 year rolling basis, renewed by each subsequent page view on the website. This cookie allows ResponseTap to link multiple visits made over time by a visitor from the same browser, unless the cookie is deletedadiVi Is a session cookie which contains a visit session ID. This cookie is used by ResponseTap to track a visitor’s browsing session, and it expires around 30 minutes after the visitor leaves the website. This allows ResponseTap to link all the visitors’ page views to their current browsing session.adiLP Contains a timestamp for the last time a ResponseTap server was contacted, in order to reserve a call tracking number for an active website visitor. It expires around 30 minutes after the visitor leaves the website.adiS Contains a server session ID used by ResponseTap systems to ensure incoming requests are assigned to an appropriate internal server for procession. It expires around 30 minutes after the visitor leaves the website.JSESSIONID DEPRECATED – Occasionally set by the ResponseTap server responsible for serving telephone numbers and contains the same value as the adiS cookie. This cookie is no longer used by the application as it has been replaced by the adiS cookie but is still occasionally set where it doesn’t currently exist. This will be removed completely in a future update. As with the adiS cookie it expires around 30 minutes after the visitor leaves the website.adiErr This is only set when a client does not have JavaScript or cookies enabled, or when ResponseTap tracking code has been incorrectly installed or formatted, or when there is a server side error. This cookie has an expiry of 30 minutes from when it is set and prevents number replacement and tracking while it exists.adiBas Only set for customers using rtap-session – a specific configuration of ResponseTap to limit which visitors are tracked and when tracking numbers are displayed based on the source they were referred from. This contains the ‘approved tracking source’ of the client and lasts for a configurable amount of time between 1 and 336 hours (14 days) from the time the visitor clicks through from an ‘approved tracking source’. For more information on ResponseTap, see the official ResponseTap page.Opt Out**Please note that when you opt out the changes will take affect when the page is reloaded or when you navigate away from this page.A legitimate interest Audit has been completed in line with GDPR3.Information that we shareAs a business we work in partnership with third parties to ensure operational effectiveness of processes and our generate status to fulfil our day to day functions. Third parties will include:Our website hosting companyOur email technology companyOur website analytics providerOur information support companyOur banking companyOur accreditation companies such as CHAS, Safe contractor, Constructionline and SSAIBWe will not sell or lease your information and we do not compile information for that purpose. No information will be provided to third parties that are not part of our business operations.4.Protecting your personal informationWe work hard to keep your personal information safe and secure by:HTTPS website – All website visits occur under the secure encryption HTTPS protocol. All enquiry and order forms will be processed on the website within the HTTPS protocolPassword policies that ensures all passwords are changed every 3 months. Should a person leave Assured we shut their access and passwords down with immediate effectInternal access restrictions – our internal software is built to only allow certain access to personal information. People are only permitted access should this be required for them to fulfil their contractual employmentFirewalls, Anti-virus, Anti-malware on all of our hardware and softwareWe review our information collection, storage and processing practices to ensure that your details are secure5.Data RetentionWe only keep your personal data for as long as is necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for as outlined in section 2, for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting or reporting requirements.To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the purposes for which we process your personal data amount whether legitimate interest, contract obligation or lead requirements, the nature and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, - and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means.In specific circumstances we may also retain your personal data for longer periods of time so that we have an accurate record of your dealings with us in the event of any complaints or challenges, or if we reasonably believe.We maintain a data retention policy which we apply to records in our care. Where your personal data is no longer required we will ensure it is either securely deleted or stored in a way which means it will no longer be used by the business. There is a prospect of litigation relating to your personal data or dealings.A copy of our retentions policy can be requested on the details below. Links to other websitesOur website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.7.Honesty and Transparency Your rights under GDPR are as outlined below:You can request access to your personal information and dataYou can update and amend your own personal information and data to keep accurateYou can request your personal information or data to be deletedYou can object to the processing of your personal information and dataYou can request that we stop processing your information and dataYou can request that your information and data be delivered to yourself or a third partyYou can object to profiling or automated decision making that could impact on youYou have the right to lodge a complaint with the information commissioner’s office.If you are unhappy about the data that we collect or the information that we are sending you, you can take control by:Not accepting cookies – when you gain access to our website you are able to not accept cookies. You can also block all cookies through your browser settings.See below links to access your web browser settingsGoogle chrome – https://www.google.comMicrosoft Edge – https://www.microsoft.comMozilla firefox – https://www.mozilla.orgApple safari – https://www.apple.comUnsubscribe which means unsubscribe – if you unsubscribe then we wont email you again. The system we use to issue you any information will not allow any future emails to be sent once you have unsubscribedIf we have any inaccurate information for you, please email us at info@assured-ltd.co.uk where we will quickly correct this for youIf you change your mind at any time write to us on the below address or email us at info@assured-ltd.co.uk and we will remove you from our systemUpdated March 2020Contact UsSheffield   0238 026 9498 London   020 3286 8301 Glasgow   0141 416 2157 Newcastle   0800 804 6266 Manchester   0161 408 0605 Milton Keynes   0845 402 3045 Birmingham   0121 288 4155   Privacy    Terms & Conditions    Disclaimer    Sitemap Regional OfficesLatest NewsChurches Fire Statement and Actions on the Coronavirus (Covid-19)CHURCHES FIRE STATEMENT AND ACTIONS ON THE CORONAVIRUS (COVID-19) Churches Fire continues to monitor the ...Top 5 Worst Retail Thefts since 2014Did you know, latest figures within the retail sector show growth in all major types ...Videos
